<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<topic xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="urn:oasis:names:tc:dita:xsd:ditabase.xsd" id="i20180103112654057" status="new">
    <title id="title">Why a style guide starter for DITA</title>
    <abstract id="abstract">DITA provides a consistent structure for content. However, <shortdesc id="a0">to get truly consistent content out of DITA, it is necessary to use a consistent syntax</shortdesc> within the elements that form the structure. This style guide starter provides a set of guidelines from which you can draw inspiration to define your own set of rules.</abstract>
    <prolog id="prolog">
        <author id="author">France Baril</author>
        <publisher id="publisher">Architextus</publisher>
        <critdates id="critdates">
            <created id="created" date="2018-01-03"/>
        </critdates> 
    </prolog>
    <body id="body">
        <section id="a1"><title id="a2">No single truth, hence a style guide starter</title>
        <p id="a3">This guide is not trying to define the way everyone should create content.</p>
        <p id="a4">Guidelines should:</p>
        <ul id="a5">
            <li id="a6">Improve the experience of your <keypoint id="a7">target audience</keypoint>. You don't address sports fan the same way you address bankers.</li>
            <li id="a8">Work for your <keypoint id="a9">specific reuse strategies</keypoint>.</li>
            <li id="a10">Support your <keypoint id="a11">business objectives</keypoint>. If you develop training material, you may need guidelines for writing learning objectives, while someone that writes maintenance guides for a nuclear power plant may be more interested in security notices.</li>
            <li id="a12">Fit your corporate (or personal) <keypoint id="a13">brand</keypoint>.</li>
        </ul>
            <p id="a14">Hence, this style guide is a starting point for teams to define their common voice.</p>
            <p id="a15">It is ok to adapt this style guide to your preferences. It is important, however, that everyone in your team follows the same guidelines. An organization should have a single style guide to maximize collaboration, reuse and avoid departmental silos.</p>
        </section>
        <section id="a16"><title id="a17">Justifying guidelines</title>
        <p id="a18">Justify guidelines to:</p>
            <ul id="a19">
                <li id="a20"><keypoint id="a21">Improve writers' compliance</keypoint>. People buy into rules when they understand their purpose. Writing in a collaborative environment and creating content for multiple contexts and media is new to most writers. Show them how most rules support reuse and business objectives.</li>
                <li id="a22"><keypoint id="a23">Avoid rules perversion</keypoint>. Following rules blindly often leads to abberations. Applying rules to the wrong context can create problems rather than solve them.</li>
                <li id="a24"><keypoint id="a25">Support maintenance</keypoint>. Some rules may need to change over time as the context evolves, when new media emerge, or when some publications become obsolete. It's easier to maintain a good set of rules when you remember why the rule was created in the 1st place.</li>
            </ul>
            
        </section>
    </body>
</topic>