<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<topic xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="urn:oasis:names:tc:dita:xsd:ditabase.xsd" id="i20180103120710672" status="new">
    <title id="title">Define a style guide per language</title>
    <abstract id="abstract">Rules in one language may or may not apply to another. <shortdesc id="shortdesc">Work with your localization vendor to adapt and create language-specific rules that are important to your target languages, even if they are incorrect or irrelevant in your source language.</shortdesc>.</abstract>
    <prolog id="prolog">
        <author id="author">France Baril</author>
        <publisher id="publisher">Architextus</publisher>
        <critdates id="critdates">
            <created id="created" date="2018-01-03"/>
        </critdates>
    </prolog>
    <body id="body">
        <section id="a0"><p id="a1">Examples of rules that must be adapted:</p>
            <ul id="a2">
            <li id="a3">The use of <keypoint id="a4">spaces around punctuation</keypoint>. There is no need to define the use of spaces before a colon, an exclamation mark or inside quotes in English. In French, however, there are spaces right inside quotes and before colons and exclamation marks. With the move to the web, some organizations have decided to remove spaces, while most now require the use of non-breaking spaces to avoid finding a colon or an exclamation point as the 1st character on a new line and to avoid the presence of widow or orphan quotes at the beginning or at the end of a line. Also, if quotes are handled by elements such as &lt;lq&gt; and &lt;q&gt;, you need to specify if you expect the system to handle spacing with character replacement or not.</li>
            <li id="a5">The use of <keypoint id="a6">the gender neutral <i id="a7">they</i></keypoint>. In English, the sentence 'Disqualify the candidate if they failed the test.' is a perfectly acceptable sentence. In most latin-based languages, using <i id="a8">they</i> for a single candidate is a grammatical error and it does nothing to solve the gender issue as there is a masculine and a feminine version of they. Even if you could avoid it, with the Spanish Usted, for example, you can't avoid the fact that the adjectives that define the person are no gender neutral. For example, you'd say if usted es pequeno for a man and si usted es pequena for a woman.</li>
            <li id="a9"><keypoint id="a10">The voice of commands in instructions</keypoint>. In English, the imperative <q id="a11">Do this</q> and <q id="a12">Turn X on</q> makes total sense. In Spanish, for example, there is a need to define if the formal <q id="a13">usted</q> applies or the more informal <q id="a14">tu</q>. Some may say, in case of doubt, always use the formal form, but if your primary audience is a group of 10 years old, the use of <q id="a15">tu</q> will make you more credible and lovable.</li>
            </ul> </section>
    </body>
</topic>